ucu.org 2006-05-15

# Privacy Policy - University Credit Union, Los Angeles, CA

University Credit Union (UCU) places a high priority on keeping member information confidential and secure. We recognize that you expect privacy and security for your personal and financial affairs. We understand the need to safeguard sensitive information about you that you have entrusted to us. The following is UCU's Privacy Policy for Member Privacy Policy and for Internet usage. 

****

**Member Privacy Policy**

The Credit Union and our affiliate, UCU Financial Center Inc. understand the importance of protecting the privacy of our members. As such, we are committed to maintaining the confidentiality of each member's financial records consistent with state and federal laws. The following sets forth our policies regarding our use and protection of your financial information. 

**Your Rights**  
You have the following rights to restrict the sharing of personal and financial information with our affiliates (companies we own or control) and outside companies that we do business with. Nothing prohibits the sharing of information necessary for us to follow the law, as permitted by law, or to give you the best service on your accounts with us. This includes sending you information about some other products or services. 

**Your Choices**  
Unless you instruct us to "Restrict Information Sharing with Companies We Own or Control (Affiliates)", we may share personal and financial information about you with our affiliated companies. For example, you may receive information on securities and insurance products from our affiliated company, MEMBERS Financial Services program, located at University Credit Union. 

Unless you instruct us to "Restrict Information Sharing With Other Companies We Do Business With To Provide Financial Products and Services," we may share personal and financial information about you with outside companies we contract with to provide financial products and services to you. For example, you may receive information about special services or product offers from companies we partner with. 

**Collection and Use of Information**  
During the course of business, we collect the information You provide to us as well as information available from public records and credit reports. We use this information about you to administer your records and Accounts, to process your transactions, to assist us in developing new products and services, to aid you in learning more about our products and services, and to fulfill any legal regulatory requirements. 

We collect non-public personal information about you from the following sources: 

  * Information we receive from you on applications or other forms; 
  * Information we obtain when verifying the information we receive from you; 
  * Information about your transactions with us, our affiliates, or others; and 
  * Information we receive from a consumer reporting agency. 

**Sharing Information with Affiliates**  
The Credit Union is affiliated with a credit union service organization, UCU Financial Center Inc. a wholly-owned subsidiary of UCU. The Credit Union and UCU Financial Center Inc. work together and share information about your accounts to provide the products and services you may want. 

**Sharing Information with Non-Affiliates (Third Parties)**  
We may disclose all the information we collect, as described above to companies that perform services on our behalf, such as check printing and data processing companies, or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. 

Generally, we share your non-public personal information with non-affiliated third parties to complete transactions and maintain Accounts and related records (such as data processing transactions and records). We may also share information with select non-affiliated third parties if: 1) you request or authorize it; 2) the information is provided to help complete a transaction initiated by you; 3) the information is provided to a consumer reporting agency in accordance with the Fair Credit Reporting Act; or 4) the disclosure otherwise is lawfully required or permitted. 

University Credit Union does not sell member information or share account numbers with independent third party marketers offering their products and services. 

At times, we may enter into agreements with other companies to provide support or service to us or for one or more of our products, such as mailing houses that assist us in delivering your statements and other promotional materials, check printing or data processing companies. Under certain circumstances, we may also enter into joint marketing agreements with other financial institutions. Before entering into relationships with such entities, we require them to agree to safeguard our members' information and to comply with all applicable privacy laws. 

There are several types of third parties with whom we may share your information. We may disclose non-public personal information about you to affiliated and non- affiliated third party financial service providers, such as mortgage bankers, securities broker-dealers, and insurance agents. 

We may also disclose non-public personal information about you to other non-affiliated third parties not described above as permitted by law. 

**Your Right to Restrict Sharing of Personal and Financial Information**  
You have the right to restrict the sharing of personal and Financial information with our affiliate (companies we own or control) and outside companies that we do business with. 

We will annually send you a form setting forth Important Privacy Choices for Consumers. You may make elections to restrict sharing of your personal and financial information by completing, signing and returning that form to us. 

If you elect to restrict the sharing of personal and financial information that election will remain unless you state otherwise. If we do not hear from you we may share some of your information as we have stated in this policy. 

**Maintaining Account Privacy in Business Relationships with Third Parties**  
Sometimes it is necessary to provide personally identifiable information about you to non-affiliated third parties for joint marketing purposes. This would be arranged with a company not affiliated with the credit union but contracted to perform certain services for the membership, such as a vendor hired to prepare statements, process credit card transactions or print check orders. These companies act on our behalf and are obligated to keep the information that we provide to them confidential.

Please ask for a form if you have not received yours or need a new one. 

**Types of Information That We May Share**  
We do no disclose any non-public personal information about our members and former members to anyone, except as required or permitted by law. 

Pursuant to the Fair Credit Reporting Act ("FCRA"), it is the Credit Union's practice to share transaction/ experience information (as defined by the FCRA) with its affiliates and nonaffiliated third parties to the extent permitted by law. 

**Third Party Links**  
From time to time various vendors such as credit card companies make certain programs available to you. In order to participate in the program you may be asked to provide them with certain personal information. We want you to know that the information you provide to those companies is subject to their privacy policy. 

**Security of Information**  
We restrict access to your non-public personal and account information to those employees who need to know that information to provide products and services to our members. Our employees access information about you when needed to administer your accounts, to provide requested services, or in response to a legally valid outside request or order (such as a subpoena). 

Our employees may also access information to exercise our rights under the law or pursuant to any agreement with you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to guard your nonpublic personal information. We also continually update and assess our systems to improve our technology for protecting information.

**Accuracy of Information**  
We strive to ensure that our records contain accurate information about you. If you see any inaccuracies in your statements, please call (310) 477-6628 or e-mail us at ucumail@ucu.org. We will promptly investigate and make any necessary changes to update your records. 

**Information Sharing in the Event of Termination of Membership**  
In addition to safeguarding information about you as an active member, if you decide to terminate your membership or become an inactive member, we will adhere to the privacy policies and practices as described in this notice. 

**Changes to Our Policy**  
We reserve the right to revise our policy as our business needs change or as the law requires. If we revise our policies, we will provide our active members with copies of our new policies at that time. 

****

**Internet Guidelines**

**Protecting Online Applications**  
When you apply online for accounts or use the Home Branch online banking service, you provide personal information that is necessary for us to process your application. To ensure that your information remains confidential, all sessions are established with Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL encrypts and decodes all data transmitted only between your browser and the UCU server. For more information on security and recommended browsers, please see the [Home Branch Security](http://www.ucu.org/hb_security.htm) on our Web site.

It is recommended that when using a browser containing any personal data, that you end the browser session so other users or persons do not have access to your personal information.

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**  
For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, UCU employs software programs to monitor Web site traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or modify information, or otherwise cause damage.

UCU also uses software programs to collect statistical information about the use of UCU's Web site and applications contained therein. Programs are used to create summary statistics, which are used for such purposes as assessing what information is of most and least interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. No personal information, such as your name or address is collected or used for this analysis. We collect no information that would identify you personally, unless you give your authorization for us to retain that information. Any data automatically stored is kept as the confidential records of the credit union and is not sold or distributed in part or whole to any third party. 

**Use of Cookies on the UCU Web Site**  
UCU only utilizes the use of cookies in its Home Branch application. For each logon session, a cookie is maintained only to verify that the user receiving the information is the user that logged on. Once you terminate your session on Home Branch, the cookie is no longer valid. 

UCU contracts with affiliated parties to provide other Web-based applications. These services, usually housed on the affiliate servers, may employ the use of cookies to administer their application. 

**Information Collected from E-mails and Web Forms**  
UCU uses personally identifiable information from an electronic mail message containing a question or comment or from a form that e-mails us information to fulfill a request for information or to respond to your requests. UCU reserves the right to store these requests to assist us in following up or maintaining service quality of requests or to provide us with information for future improvements to our Web site. We may forward your electronic message or request to other employees who are better able to respond to your particular need. We do not create individual profiles with the information you provide. UCU may keep e-mail addresses or data that you personally authorize us to keep (for internal marketing or promotional purposes).

**Links to Other Sites**  
To provide you with greater access of information, UCU maintains a list of links to other sites. This is provided as a service to our membership. UCU has no control over these sites and is not responsible for the contents or privacy practices of these sites. UCU makes no warranty about the quality or adequacy of services provided by or through these other sites with respect to services and products provided nor whether these sites will maintain the confidentiality of member information or whether the information will be distributed to other third parties.

Effective 7/1/04
